<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forward Error Correction blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Forward Error Correction blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:13:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: June 17-21</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 10:13:12 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week4/</guid>
      <description>Continued progress on AFF3CT Turbo codec implementation in OOT module Last week, I continued to work on implementing the Turbo encoder and decoder blocks in GNU Radio. The blocks call the AFF3CT library to encode/decode the input vector, but the encoder block&amp;rsquo;s output is not right.&#xA;I started using the debugger in VS Code to step through the code. This was helpful as I was dealing with segmentation faults and needed to track down where the code was accessing invalid memory (with the help of my mentors).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: June 10-14</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 10:13:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week3/</guid>
      <description>Later after reading my week 2 blog post, I realized I incorrectly said that my week 2 goal was to implement the next 3 codecs. (While I was writing my proposal, I had written that as my week 2 goal in one draft.) My week 2 goal was actually to test the turbo parallel block, write QA codes, and document the new blocks. Adding, testing, and documenting the BCH, RS, and RA codecs was the Weeks 3-4 (June 10-21) goal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: June 3-7</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 10:01:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week2/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the first two weeks, I am unfortunately behind schedule. Setting up the development environment so that I can work in-tree has required troubleshooting every step of the way. Based on my issues, I plan to update the MacOS installation guide on the wiki in the next few weeks, or at least point out some outdated instructions.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start working on new blocks in an OOT module called fec_dev before moving my code over to the main tree.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: May 28-31</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 15:10:24 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/week1/</guid>
      <description>This summer, I am contributing to GNU Radio through Google Summer of Code. I recently completed my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Electrical Engineering, and I&amp;rsquo;m starting a PhD program in Networks/Communications in the fall. My project involves overhauling GNU Radio&amp;rsquo;s forward error correction (FEC) / error coding package (gr-fec).&#xA;Other open source libraries like AFF3CT (https://aff3ct.github.io/) include additional FEC implementations compared to GNU Radio. I will add FEC techniques from AFF3CT&amp;rsquo;s library into GNU Radio and develop a testbench to compare throughput and error rate for different techniques and implementations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
